Finding Aid for the Jesse Ely Wills Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Prospective Staff (Box 16)
- Prospective Faculty (1960) (Box 16)
- Staff: A (Box 16)
- Staff: Ackerman, David (Box 16)
- Staff: Allen, Robert F. (Box 16)
- Staff: Allinsmith, Wesley (Box 16)
- Staff: Alpern, Jerry (Box 16)
- Staff: Aronson, Carolyn (Box 16)
- Staff: Austrin, Dr. Harvey R. (Box 16)
- Staff: B (Box 16)
- Staff: Barry, John B. (Box 16)
- Staff: Bartlett, Claude Jackson (Box 16)
- Staff: Botwinick, Jack (Dr.) (Box 16)
- Staff: Bower, Warren (Box 16)
- Staff: Bowers, Mary W. (Dr.) (Box 16)
- Staff: Bowman, Paul (Box 16)
- Staff: Broedel, John W. (Box 16)
- Staff: C (Box 16)
- Staff: Campbell, Ernest C. (Box 16)
- Staff: Cansler, G.M. (Box 16)
- Staff: Cantor, Gordon (Box 16)
- Staff: Cantor, Joan Harris (Box 16)
- Staff: Clapp, Chester D. (Box 16)
- Staff: Cook, Murray (Box 16)
- Staff: Cook, Jerome (Box 16)
- Staff: Crites, John 0. (Box 16)
- Staff: Culver, Wayne (Box 16)
- Staff: D (Box 16)
- Staff: Davids, Anthony (Box 16)
- Staff: Davis, Junius A. (Dr.) (Box 16)
- Staff: Dinoff, Michael (Box 16)
- Staff: Dutton and Stout (Box 16)
- Staff: E (Box 16)
- Staff: Ellingson, Dr. R.J. (Box 16)
- Staff: Evon, Leonard (Dr.) (Box 16)
- Staff: F (Box 16)
- Staff: Fisher, Seymour (Box 16)
- Staff: Flynn, John P. (Dr.) (Box 16)
- Staff: Foshee, James (Box 16)
- Staff: Fricke, Benno Gerry (Box 16)
- Staff: Froehlich, Dean (Box 16)
- Staff: G (Box 16)
- Staff: Gallaher, James J. (Box 16)
- Staff: Garner, Ann Margaret (Dr.) (Box 16)
- Staff: Garrison, Mortimer (Dr.) (Box 16)
- Staff: Gazda, George (Box 16)
- Staff: Getz, Steven (Box 16)
- Staff: Girardeau, Fred (Box 16)
- Staff: Goer, Marvin H. (Box 16)
- Staff: Goliman, Bernard (Box 16)
- Staff: Gillin, Eugene S. (Box 16)
- Staff: Gordon, Mordecai (Box 16)
- Staff: H (Box 16)
- Past Faculty: Haberle, Ann (Box 16)
- Staff: Hardy, Virginia Smith (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Hathway, Starke R. (Box 17)
- Staff: Hill, Julius (Box 17)
- Staff: Hook, Mrs. Marion Emerson (Box 17)
- Staff: Hoyt, Kenneth B. (Box 17)
- Staff: Hudson, Margaret (Box 17)
- Staff: Hurder, William P. (Box 17)
- Staff: Hurley, John Richard (Box 17)
- Staff: Hurst, John G. (Box 17)
- Staff: Hylbert, Kenneth W. (Box 17)
- Staff: I (Box 17)
- Hobbs Desk: Faculty - Clyde T. Jelton (Box 17)
- Staff: J (Box 17)
- Staff: John, William F. (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Jordan, Jean (Box 17)
- Staff: Jourard, Sidney (Box 17)
- Staff: K (Box 17)
- Staff: Kaiser, Richard L. (Box 17)
- Staff: King, Frederick A. (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: King, Robert A. (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Koile, Earl A. (Box 17)
- Staff: L (Box 17)
- Prospective Faculty Member: Lamont, James F. (Box 17)
- Staff: Lansing, Robert W. (Box 17)
- Staff: Leland, Henry (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Levy, Leon H. (Box 17)
- Hobbs Desk: Paul R. Lohnes (Prospective) (Box 17)
- Staff: Longabaugh, Richard (Box 17)
- Staff: Loos, Frank M. (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Loret, Peter (Box 17)
- Staff: Lotsof, Erwin J. (Box 17)
- Staff: Luchins, A.S. (Box 17)
- Faculty: Lucito, Leonard (Box 17)
- Staff: Lundy, Richard M. (Box 17)
- Staff: M (Box 17)
- Staff: McCleary, Robert A. (Box 17)
- Staff: McMahill, Patricia (Box 17)
- Staff: Madow, Arnold (Box 17)
- Staff: Mancuso, James Carmen (Box 17)
- Staff: Manis, Melvin (Box 17)
- Staff: Martin, Jim (Box 17)
- Staff: Meer, Bernard (Box 17)
- Staff: Meister, David E. (Box 17)
- Prospective Faculty Mental Deficiency Program
- Staff: Mentzter, Don (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Millon, Theodore (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Moskowitz, Bernard (Box 17)
- Staff: N (Box 17)
- Staff: Neff, Franklin W. (Box 17)
- Staff: Nelson, Kenneth G. (Box 17)
- Staff: Nolan, William J. (Box 17)
- Prospective Staff: Norton, Dee (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: 0 (Box 17)
- Staff: O'Connor, Neil (Box 17)
- Staff: O'Dea, J. David (Box 17)
- Staff: Osburn, Hobert G. (Box 17)
- Staff: P (Box 17)
- Staff: Pattishall, Evan G. Jr. (Box 17)
- Staff: Pickens, Mary Burkheimer (Box 17)
- Staff: Q (Box 17)
- Staff: Quay, Lorene C. (Box 17)
- Staff: R (Box 17)
- Staff: Rafferty, Janet (Box 17)
- Staff: Robertson, Malcolm (Box 17)
- Staff: Rosenblum, Sidney (Box 17)
- Staff: Rosen, Bernard (Box 17)
- Prospective Faculty: Rosner, Benjamin (Box 17)
- Staff: Rosenberg, B.G. (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Ross, Leonard E. (Box 17)
- Staff: Rushlau, Perry J. Jr. (Box 17)
- Staff: S (Box 17)
- Applications for Secretarial Positions (miscellaneous) (Box 17)
- Staff: Seashore, Charles (Box 17)
- Staff: Shed, Dr. Charles (Box 17)
- Staff: Shenfeld, Nathan (Box 17)
- Prospective Faculty: Schutz, Richard E. (Box 17)
- Staff: Simmons, Persis White (Box 17)
- Staff: Sloan, William (Box 17)
- Staff: Smith, Howard P. (Box 17)
- Staff: Spielberger, Charles D. (Box 17)
- Staff! Stevens, Phyliss (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Stotsky, Bernard A. (Box 17)
- Staff: Stout and Dutton (Box 17)
- Staff: T (Box 17)
- Staff: Taylor, Jack (Box 17)
- Staff: Teitelbaum, Phillip (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Thompson, Robert (Box 17)
- Staff: Tiedeman, David (Box 17)
- Staff: Trippe, Matthew J. (Box 17)
- Staff: U (Box 17)
- Staff: V (Box 17)
- Staff: Verberg, Wallace (Box 17)
- Staff: Vidulich, Robert Nicholas (Box 17)
- Staff: W (Box 17)
- Staff: Warnath, Charles (Box 17)
- Staff: Warnken, Robert (Box 17)
- Staff: Wegener, Jerome (Dr.) (Box 17)
- Staff: Weiss, Robert Frank (Box 17)
- Staff: West, Earl (Box 17)
- Staff: Windle, Charles (Box 17)
- Staff: Winer, Ben James (Box 17)
- Staff: Wolf, Irwin s. (Box 17)
- Staff: Wolin, Burton R. (Box 17)
- Staff: X, Y, Z (Box 17)
- Reprints (Box 17)
- Student IQ Testing Materials (individualized envelopes) (Box 18)
- Anderson, Murray (Box 18)
- Bolton, Robert (Box 18)
- Boyce, Mary Francis (Box 18)
- Bradford, Eleanor (Box 18)
- Carlisle, Mary E. (Box 18)
- Cumming, Fairman P. (Box 18)
- Diamond, Flossie (Box 18)
- Dycus, Charles (Box 18)
- Feldman, Sheryl (Box 18)
- Frank, Mary Jane (Box 18)
- Frank, Stanley (Box 18)
- Giddings, Thomas (Box 18)
- Harap, Elena (Box 18)
- Hearn, Nancy Conner (Box 18)
- Jackson, Carolyn (Box 18)
- Kinestrick, Walter (Box 18)
- Lebeck, Ann (Box 18)
- LeCornu, John (Box 18)
- Lewis, Coleen (Box 18)
- Lindman, Erick Leroy, Jr. (Ricky) (Box 18)
- Long, Patricia (Box 18)
- McCall, John (Box 18)
- McKinney, Sally (Box 18)
- Parman, Bettye (Box 18)
- Rittenberg, Alan (Box 18)
- Roark, Ronald (Box 18)
- Rosenblum, Carolyn (Box 18)
- Student Testing Materials (Box 18)
- Scott, Leslie (Box 19)
- Story, Roby Ann (Box 19)
- Thackston, George William (Box 19)
- Treadway, Richard (Box 19)
- Van Til, Jon (Box 19)
- Whitaker, Margaret (Box 19)
- Wolfe, Charlotte (Box 19)
- Case Studies (14 folders) (Box 19)
- Seyfret, Carl (Box 19)
- Sullivan, Juana (Box 19)
- Anderson, Robert C. (Dr.) (Box 19)
- Miscellaneous folders (12) (Box 19)
- News clippings (Box 20)
- Request for reprints on the Gifted Child Project (Box 20)
- Autobiographies (Student Research Project M-674) (Box 20)
- Research Project - Directions for the Preparation of an (Box 20)
- Autobiography (7/15/58) (Box 20)
- The Citadel Class Fund (1960) (Box 20)
- General Correspondence (A - W) (Box 20)
- [20 written on box lid]'. v ] 1 (Box 21)
- 1. General Correspondence (X - Z; I - J) (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Committee on National Defense Education Act (Box 21, Folder 3.18)
- Veterans Administration (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 4.37)
- Veterans Administration Program (miscellaneous) (Box 21, Folder 4.37)
- Catalog Materials (Box 21, Folder 4.32)
- Reflector Replies (Box 21, Folder 4.5)
- Test Scores (Box 21, Folder 4.4)
- Social Science Research Council (Box 21, Folder 8.14)
- Joint Commission - Final Report (Box 21, Folder 8.4)
- Health Information Foundation- Progress in Health Services (Box 21, Folder 8.17)
- Mental Health Services (Atlanta) -Department of Health, Education and Welfare (Box 21, Folder 8.18)
- Joint Commission on Mental Illness and Health (Box 21, Folder 8.4)
- NIMH: Training Committee - Fisk Cooperative Psychology Project (Box 21, Folder 8.51)
- NIMH: Alcoholism Commission (Box 21, Folder 8.53)
- Conference Board of Association Research Councils Committee on International Exchange of Persons Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 8.7)
- Conference Board of Associated Councils Committee on International Exchange of Persons (December 13 and 14, 1957) (Box 21, Folder 8.71)
- 8.71a Fulbright Meeting (June, 1959) (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Conference Board of Associated Research Councils (November 8, 1958 meeting) (Box 21, Folder 8.72)
- University of Pennsylvania Institute For Executives 8.81 University of Wisconsin Work - Conference (11/10-13/60) (Box 21, Folder 8.8)
- American Association for Gifted Children (Box 21, Folder 8.9)
- Maryland State Department of Education - Committee on Superior and Gifted Children (Baltimore, 2/11/60) (Box 21, Folder 8.91)
- Tennessee Commission on Youth Guidance (Box 21, Folder 8.92)
- NCA STS Omaha (July, 1959) (Box 21, Folder 8.93)
- Thayer Hospital - Topic: "Some Psychological Aspects of the Nurse's Role in Helping People Get Well" (October 8, 1957) (Box 21, Folder 11.4)
- ICEC Meeting, Kansas City (April, 1958) (Box 21, Folder 11.5)
- Kansas City Speech Miscellaneous, unfoldered materials: "Of Mice and Children," a paper read to the Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development, by Nicholas Hobbs (March 1, 1959) [3 copies] Several Group Therapy Studies (transcribed sessions from 1950s) (Box 21, Folder 11.6)
- (21 written on box lid): (Box 22)
- Bigelow Committee (Box 22)
- Registration (Box 22)
- Caswell's Committee (Box 22)
- 38ITA (Box 22)
- Teachers College Staff (Box 22)
- Veterans Administration (Box 22)
- 3191CA (Box 22)
- Hobbs - Carbons and Recordings of Combined Groups 200 (Box 22)
- Miel Committee (Box 22)
- Staff - Current (Box 22)
- Veterans Administration (Box 22)
- Eastern Psychological Association (Box 22)
- Group Therapy (Box 22)
- Brooklyn (Box 22)
- Research - A.I.R. Criterion Data (Box 22, Folder 4.63)
- Research - A.I.R. Interview Daily Reports (Box 22, Folder 4.64)
- Research - A.I.R. Final Evaluation Reports (Box 22, Folder 4.65)
- Research - A.I.R. Charts for Pilot Attitude Paper (Box 22, Folder 4.66)
- Research - A.I.R. Personal Planning Questionnaire (Box 22, Folder 4.67)
- Research - A.I.R. Interview Materials (Box 22, Folder 4.73)
- Research - A.I.R. Miscellaneous Notes (Box 22, Folder 4.69)
- Research - A.I.R. Interview Recording and Typescript Rating (Box 22, Folder 4.68)
- Research - A.I.R. Interview Project (Box 22, Folder 4.70)
- Research - A.I.R. Interview Project - S.O.P. (Box 22, Folder 4.71)
- Research - A.I.R. Interview Project (Box 22, Folder 4.72)
- A.I.R. Airline Safety Project (Box 22, Folder 4.74)
- Social Science Research Council A.I.R. Research - Incomplete Sentences (Box 22, Folder 4.75)
- Incomplete Sentences (Pilot) - Results of Analysis Miscellaneous Materials (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 4.80)
- (22 written on box lid): (Box 23)
- Miscellaneous: "Introduction: Interpersonal Perceptions of Four Couples (Eight Subjects) in Nondirective Group Therapy, 11 by Everett A. Daloan (Box 23)
- Education 320 SC (Departmental Project Conference and Seminar in Guidance (Box 23)
- Proposed Dissertation Outlines (Box 23)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 23)
- Ed. D. Committee (Box 23)
- Education 320 lC (Spring, 1950) (Box 23)
- (Midterm Examination) Education 220PA: Personality Development and Mental Hygiene (Box 23)
- Manual from Guidance Laboratory - Education 319-320 IC (Box 23)
- Desk File - Psychology 202 (Box 23, Folder 9.1)
- Desk File - Psychology 120 and 220 (Box 23)
- Ethics Manuscripts (Box 23)
- 14 Desk File - Junior Division (Box 23, Folder 14)
- 10 Desk File - Journal Club (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Courses - Education 282M: Bibliography and Book Lists 8 Desk File - Psychology 51 (Box 23, Folder 13.06)
- Education 220 PA - Personal Development and Mental Hygiene (General) (Box 23, Folder 20.01)
- Education 220 PA - Student Rosters (Box 23, Folder 20.02)
- Education 220 PA - Lecture Notes (Box 23, Folder 20.03)
- Education 220 PA - Reports (Box 23, Folder 20.05)
- Education 220 PA - Bibliography and Book Lists (Box 23, Folder 20.06)
- Education 282P (Spring, 1950) - Examinations (Box 23)
- Rating Scale for Courses in Psychological Services (Box 23)
- 319 IC - Purposes ~ped for S.P.A. Students (Box 23, Folder 11.11)
- Education 319 IC -Case Records (Box 23, Folder 11.10)
- Education 319 IC - Individual Counseling (General) (Box 23, Folder 11.01)
- Education 319 IC - Student Rosters (Box 23, Folder 11.02)
- Education 319 IC - Lecture Notes (Box 23, Folder 11.03)
- Education 319 IC - Examinations (Box 23, Folder 11.04)
- Education 319 IC - Reports (Box 23, Folder 11.05)
- Education 319 IC -Bibliography and Book Lists (Box 23, Folder 11.06)
- Education 319 IC - Supplies and Equipment (Box 23, Folder 11.07)
- Manual from Guidance Laboratory for Students in Education 319 IC (Spring, 1947) (Box 23, Folder 11.09)
- Education 319 SC- 320 SC: Departmental Project Conference and Seminar in Guidance (Box 23, Folder 14.01)
- Education 281 0 - Orientation to Psychological Services (1946-194 7) (Box 23, Folder 15.01)
- Education 281 0 - Bibliography (Box 23, Folder 15.02)
- Stencils (Box 23, Folder 15.09)
- Education 381 TP - Student Rosters (Box 23, Folder 16.02)
- Manual From Guidance Laboratory - Education 381 TA (Box 23, Folder 16.03)
- Education 381 TA - Examinations (Box 23, Folder 16.04)
- Education 381 TP - Reports (Box 23, Folder 16.05)
- Education 381 TP - Bibliography and Book Lists (Box 23, Folder 16.06)
- Education 381 TP - Supplies and Equipment (Box 23, Folder 16.07)
- Education 220 PA - Supplies and Equipment (Box 23, Folder 20.07)
- Education 220 PA (Midterm Examinations) (Box 23)
- Education 220 PA (Final Examinations) (Box 23)
- Education 220 MH (Mental Hygiene) (Box 23, Folder 21.01)
- Education 200 MH (Mental Hygiene - Student Rosters) (Box 23, Folder 21.03)
- Education 200 MH (Mental Hygiene - Lecture Notes) (Box 23, Folder 21.03)
- Education 200 MH (Mental Hygiene - Examinations) (Box 23, Folder 21.04)
- Education 200 MH (Mental Hygiene -Reports) (Box 23, Folder 21.05)
- Education 200 MH (Mental Hygiene - Bibliography and Book Lists) (Box 23, Folder 21.06)
- Education ~00 MH (Mental Hygiene - Supplies and Equipment) (Box 23, Folder 21.07)
- Education 281 TR, Rorschach (General) Rorschach Records (Completed) (Box 23, Folder 22.01)
- Education 382 M (Final Examination) (Box 23, Folder 24.00)
- Clinical Materials - Explanations in Group Counseling (Box 23)
- Group Therapy (Racial and Religious Groups) Miscellaneous (Box 23)
- Explorations in Individual Counseling
- Manual for the Minnesota Multiphasic Personality Inventory (Hathaway and McKinley) (Box 23)
- Clinical Materials: Case of Hitchcock (Box 23)
- Psychological Services Branch: AAF Convalescent Hospital (Box 23)
- Suggestive Outline and Sample Questions for Initial and Intensive Interviews (Box 23)
- Clinical Materials - This Week - Magazine Story on Convalescent Hospital (11 August 1945) (Box 23)
- Clinical Materials - "Talk to Student Body of Mercer University" (13 August 1945) (Box 23)
- Clinical Materials - Services Offered by the Psychological Service Branch (Cochran Field) (Box 23)
- Clinical Materials - Group Psychotherapy (Cochran Notes) (Box 23)
- (23 written on box lid): (Box 24)
- Clinical Materials Group Psychotherapy (offprints) (Box 24)
- W-4 Forms, pay vouchers, expense vouchers, time sheets, small supply A. I. R. stationery Personal: Army Records (1942) Army Records (Hobbs) 201 file (1941-1943) Personal: Army Records (Hobbs) 201 file (1944-1945) Manuscripts: Bibliography - Play Therapy (Box 24)
- Bibliography: Synder - Nondirective Therapy (Box 24, Folder 5.1)
- Bibliography: Play Therapy (Box 24, Folder 5.2)
- Bibliography: Test Service Bulletin (Box 24, Folder 5.3)
- Bibliography: The Commonwealth Fund Publications (1946) (Box 24, Folder 5.4)
- A Bibliography for the Student of Group Therapy (Box 24, Folder 5.5)
- Bibliography: Audio-Visual and Teacher Education (Box 24, Folder 5.6)
- Education 281-282: Introduction to the Rorshach Method (Bibliography) (Box 24, Folder 5.7)
- Bibliography: Books on Psychotherapy (Box 24, Folder 5.8)
- Departmental Business: Group Work Program (Box 24, Folder 2.9)
- Departmental Business: Teachers College Surveys (Box 24, Folder 2.08)
- Case Notes: Abrams, Marcelle (Box 24, Folder 8.1)
- Case Notes: Leonard, Glove (Box 24, Folder 8.2)
- Departmental Business (Teachers College: General Planning) (Box 24, Folder 2.10)
- Counseling Cases - Brooklyn (Box 24, Folder 8.3)
- "Case Studies of a Comparative Study of Book Reviews" (xeroxed copy) (Box 24)
- The Personal Counselor (Box 24)
- Manuscripts: Teaching and Nondirective Therapy (Box 24, Folder 6.1)
- Manuscripts: "An Open Letter to the Mother of a Stuttering Child" (Box 24, Folder 6.2)
- Manuscripts: "Experimental Contributions to Mental Hygiene" (Box 24, Folder 6.3)
- Manuscripts: " A Technique for the Quantitative Analysis of Group Therapy" (Box 24, Folder 6.4)
- Manuscripts: "Basic Problems in the Training of High School Counselors" (Box 24, Folder 6.5)
- Manuscripts: "Marginal Notes on a Discussion of Freedom, Authority, and Discipline" (Box 24, Folder 6.6)
- Manuscripts: Review of Axline, Virginia Mae. Play Therapy. (Box 24, Folder 6.7)
- Manuscripts: Review of Snyder, William U. Casebook of Nondirective Counseling. (Box 24, Folder 6.8)
- Manuscript: Axline, V.M. "Some Observations on Play Therapy" (Box 24, Folder 6.9)
- Manuscripts: Malamud, Daniel I. "Central Harlem Street Clubs Research Plans" (Box 24, Folder 6.10)
- Manuscript: Mental Physiology (Box 24, Folder 6.11)
- Manuscript: "The Development and Validation of an Incomplete Sentences Test for the Selection of Airline Pilots" (Box 24, Folder 6.12)
- "My Understanding of Some Aspects of Nondirective Therapy on the Morning of October 23, 1947." (Box 24, Folder 6.13)
- "A Tentative Formulation of Hypotheses That May Serve as Guide Posts for the Counselors or Psychotherapist," by G.P. Driscoll (Box 24, Folder 6.14)
- Manuscript: "Talk on Group Psychotherapy" (Box 24, Folder 6.15)
- "Group Psychotherapy in Preventive Mental Hygiene" (Box 24, Folder 6.16)
- Wilson: Incomplete Sentences Test (Box 24, Folder 6.17)
- Notes for Talk on Nondirective Therapy (Box 24, Folder 6.18)
- "Group Therapy Approach to Problems of Human Adjustment" (Box 24, Folder 6.20)
- Arthur Combs, "Some Dynamic Aspects of Nondirective Therapy" (Box 24, Folder 6.21)
- Manuscript: "A Comprehensive Theory of Personality and Behavior," by Carl R. Rogers (Box 24, Folder 6.22)
- Manuscript: "The Effects of Individual and Group Play Therapy on the Reading Level of Retarded Readers" (Box 24, Folder 6.23)
- Manuscript: "Notes on Discussion Group Following Symposium on Implications of Current Research in Psychotherapy" (Box 24, Folder 6.24)
- Manuscripts: "Comparison of Means of Matched Samples" (Box 24, Folder 6.25)
- Manuscript: "Tension in Teachers College" (Box 24, Folder 6.26)
- Manuscripts: "Answering a Bigot: A Report of an Action Research Project" (Box 24, Folder 6.27)
- Guidance in Education (notes for a talk to the P.T.A. of Long Island, November 8, 1948) (Box 24, Folder 6.30/6.28)
- Some Comments on the Training of Applied Psychologists (Box 24, Folder 6.29)
- Clinical Psychology and Psychiatry (Box 24, Folder 6.30)
- "An Exploration of Fantasy Through the Movement and Time Dimensions in a Projective Stimulus" (Box 24, Folder 6.31)
- Manuscript: "Guidance and Some Recent Developments in Psychological Theory" (Box 24, Folder 6.33)
- Manuscript: "Definition of Self-Acceptance and Respect" (Box 24, Folder 6.32)
- Manuscripts: "The Significance of the Self-Regarding Attitudes and Perceptions" (Box 24, Folder 6.35)
- Explorations In Individual Counseling (Box 24)
- Seminar Held at Veterans Administration (Box 24, Folder 6.36)
- Summary Regarding Pennhurst State School (Box 24, Folder 6.37)
- Survey of Current Research in Client-Centered Therapy (Box 24, Folder 6.38)
- Manuscript: Explorations in Individual Counseling (Box 24, Folder 6.39)
- (24 written on box lid): (Box 25)
- The Reaction of the Counselor to the Rest of the Educational Program (Box 25, Folder 6.40)
- Community Recognition of the Gifted (Box 25, Folder 6.41)
- Manuscript: Some Viewpoints in Psychotherapy in February, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 6.42)
- Manuscript: Notes of the Role of Appraisal In Psychotherapy (Box 25, Folder 6.44)
- Manuscript: A Study of Reopened Personal Counseling Cases (Box 25, Folder 6.45)
- Manuscript: A Six Month Follow-Up of the Effects of Personal Adjustment Counseling of 498 Veterans (Box 25, Folder 6.46)
- Manuscript: Some Reflections on Empirical Investigations of Ethics (Box 25, Folder 6.47)
- Manuscript: "Power and the Personal Point of View" (Ruston, Louisiana; March 3, 1951) (Box 25, Folder 6.49)
- Manuscript: "Power and the Personal Point of View" (Jackson, Mississippi; March 16, 1951) (Box 25, Folder 6.50)
- Manuscript: An Index of Adjustment and Values (Box 25, Folder 6.51)
- Manuscript: Personality Theory and Psychotherapeutic Approaches (Box 25, Folder 6.52)
- Manuscript: Notes for Talk with Freshman of Opportunity Day, LSU, April 9, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 6.53)
- Manuscript: "Alder's Place in Psychology," by Lewis Way (Box 25, Folder 6.54)
- Manuscript: Abstract - Insight in Short Term Psychotherapy Miscellany (miscellaneous tests) (Box 25, Folder 6.47)
- Miscellany (BInet Tests) (Box 25, Folder 7.3)
- Miscellany (Tests Forms - Syracuse Test Series) (Box 25, Folder 7.4)
- Biographical Material (Box 25, Folder 7.5)
- Clippings (Box 25, Folder 7.6)
- Academic Freedom - Gundlach Case (Box 25, Folder 7.7)
- Louisiana State University (Box 25, Folder 7.12)
- Reprint File (Box 25, Folder 7.08)
- (Reprint:) Standards for Appraising Psychological Research (Wolfle) (Box 25)
- (Reprint:) "Counseling and Psychotherapy in Public Mental Health Work," by Joseph M. Bobbitt (Box 25)
- (Reprint:) "Laziness and Inertia," by Karen Horney, M.D. (Box 25)
- Notes on Child Development ILG (Box 25, Folder 7.10)
- Columbia University Seminar in Religion and Health Denver Convention Projects for Ph.D.s (Married and Single Groups) (Box 25, Folder 7.11)
- Group Therapy - Race Prejudice Reprints by Other Authors (Box 25, Folder 4.05)
- Columbia University Seminar on Religion and Health (Box 25, Folder 9.01)
- Courses: Education 200 MG2 (Box 25, Folder 17.01)
- Courses: Education 219 PA - Psychology of Adjustment (General) (Box 25, Folder 12.01)
- Courses: Education 219 PA - Student Rosters (Box 25, Folder 12.02)
- Courses: Education 219 PA - Lecture Notes (Box 25, Folder 12.03)
- Courses: Education 219 PA - Reports (Box 25, Folder 12.05)
- Courses: Education 219 PA - Bibliography and Book Lists (Box 25, Folder 12.06)
- Courses: Education 219 PA - Supplies and Equipment (Box 25, Folder 12.07)
- Courses: Education 221A (Box 25, Folder 18.01)
- Courses: Education 249T -Vocational Testing (Box 25, Folder 19.01)
- Miscellaneous Mimeographed Ethics Materials
- Outline of Handbook on Ethical Standards for Psychologists
- Committee on Guidance Practices (General) (Box 25)
- Committee on Guidance Practices (Evidence) (Box 25)
- Committee on Counseling, Y.M.C.A. Psychology Corporation (Box 25)
- Counselor Training Committee (APA) (Box 25)
- Program of Self-Certification in the Specialties (Box 25)
- Extracts from By-Laws, Section on Employment and Vocational Guidance (Box 25)
- Plan for Certification
- Committee Reports
- Committee on Public Service Standards in Social Psychology Research
- Committee on Scientific and Professional Ethics (APA) (Box 25)
- Committee on the Survey of Clinics in the State of New York (Box 25)
- Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues
- Constitution of the N.Y.S.A.A.P. (Box 25)
- Legislation for Licensing Psychologists in New Yok Developing a
- Code of Ethics for Psychologists (January, 1949; APA Journal) (Box 25)